EMMANUEL IKECHUKWU IHETU

DATA SCIENTIST

Email: ihetuemmanuel@gmail.com

Tel: +2347035012384

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

My specialists include quick learning, problem solving and responsive design principles. So far, I have Python and Rprogramming language for statistical implementation and data analytics. oracle SQL developer for database management system, Microsoft power BI for business analytics.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Programming Languages: Python & RStudio
- Database: SQL (Oracle SQL developer)
- Operating system: Windows
- Analytic/Machine Learning framework: Excel, Microsoft power Bi, Pandas, NumPy, ggplot, IBM
 SPSS Statistics, Minitab, Pytorch, TensorFlow, Apache Spark, Juypter Notebook, Clustering, Decision tree,
 AWS machine learning infrastructure.
- Skills: Data Analysis, Big Data Analysis, predictive modeling, Trend forecasting, time series, time series analysis Deep learning, Machine, Database and cloud infrastructure, AWS machine learning specialty.
- Others: clickup, talk.to, GIS cloud services, Microsoft office.

EXPERIENCE:

INNOWISE GROUP www.innowise-group.com

Innowise Group is a software development and IT consulting company that was founded in 2007. It's a company that serves IT and non-IT organizations, helping to achieve a variety of goals and objectives with digital solutions and recent trend technologies.

DATA SCIENTIST: (JANUARY 2022 TILL DATE)

- Using automated tools to extract data from primary and secondary sources
- Removing corrupted data and fixing coding errors and related problems
- Developing and maintain databases, data systems reorganizing data in a readable format
- Performing analysis to assess quality and meaning of data
- Filter Data by reviewing reports and performance indicators to identify and correct code problems
- Using statistical tools to identify, analyze, and interpret patterns and trends in complex data sets that Could be helpful for the diagnosis and prediction
- Assigning numerical value to essential business functions so that business performance can be assessed and compared over periods of time.

- Analyzing local, national, and global trends that impact both the organization and the industry
- Responsible for troubleshooting various computer issues and implementing solutions for Novotel.
- Monitoring and troubleshooting issues with python.
- Built Streaming services for real time processing of 100,000 users using Java and Scala
- Improvement performance of existing ETL processes and SQL queries for weekly CRM summary data
- Lead migration of a legacy Data Warehouse from On-premise to AWS and Java/Spark
- Developed infrastructure to process 15 TB/day resulting into 8% increase in online sales of Adtech division

•

- Machine learning program research.
- Manage configuration changes to various product devices.
- Installed and managed various python projects.

LLOYDANT BUSINESS SERVICE www.lloydant.com

Lloydant business services is one of the fastest growing technology consulting company located in Enugu that provides IT solutions to institutions and business/companies.

DATA ANALYST: (JANUARY 2020 -2021)

- Conducted research on development and designing of sample methodologies, and analyzed data for pricing
- Investigated market sizing, competitive analysis and positioning for product feasibility.
- Worked on Business forecasting, segmentation analysis and Data mining.
- Generated graphs and reports using ggplot package in RStudio for analytical models.
- Developed predictive models using Decision Tree, Random Forest and Naïve Bayes.
- Deployed recommendation engine to production, to conditionally recommend other menu items based on pas order history, increasing average order size by 7%
- Collaborated with product managers to perform cohort analysis that identified an opportunity to reduce pricing by 21% for a segment of users to boost yearly revenue by #20,000000
- Collaborating with dev-ops teams for production deployment
- Partnered with the product team to create a production recommendation engine in python that improves the average length page for users in incremented annual revenue

SOLUTION DELIVERY OFFICER: (MAY 2019- DECEMBER 2020)

- Report to the Chief Operating Officer, Responsible for the development of custom solutions and implementation of those solutions for strategic customers. This position spans the sales and pursuit cycle, implementation of new solutions and ongoing operational execution of the contract.
- Responsible for balancing the response to client demands and responsible for conducting client meetings, maintaining relationships and gathering requests and requirements. Implementation of solutions and adherence to timelines and deliverables, as well as being able to spot areas for sales growth or the need for improvement.

ENUGU ELECTRICITY DISTRIBUTION COMPANY (EEDC) www.enugudisco.com

Enugu Electricity Distribution company is the biggest utility company that focus on disturbing power to the eastern part of Nigeria, which covers five (5) states, with large population that comprises of residency and industries.

ORACLE SQL DEVELOPER: (2017-2019)

- Designed and developed analytic and reporting solutions using Oracle PL/SQL and MOD PL/SQL.
- Designed and developed data management applications for reporting solutions using Oracle Application Express.
- Developed reports on relational and multidimensional data sources.
- Developed data warehouse models and processes.

MTN NIGERIA www.mtn.com

MTN is the biggest telecommunication company in Africa which is location in more than 10 countries in Africa with high network coverage.

TECHNICAL SUPPORT OFFICER (2015 - 2016)

- Recruit and manage data capture personnel to operate the SIM REG Netbook.
- Organizing teams to cover all key channels with high human traffic.
- Ensure that all data captured are uploaded onto the SIM REG server within 24 hours.
- troubleshooting, maintain, install, and overall supervision of data equipment.

EDUCATION:

- Information technology (Msc INVIEW)
- BSc Computer Science [UPPER CREDIT]

REFEREES:

On Request